our next graduation story takes place in
the happy pot field Hills of Colorado
have you heard this story about the
valedictorian of a Colorado High School
being barred from delivering his
graduation speech because in that speech
he planned to reveal that he was
gay he was barred because he was going
to say he was gay what's going on
graduation you can't shout out you can't
come out
seriously next thing you know that
they're going to want you to wear pants
under those robes
Larry said when speaking about a
friend okay fine so douchy principal
wouldn't let this valid dictorian come
out of the closet in the speech but but
why was he barred from speaking I made
all the edits if they asked me to I just
refused to take out the part where I say
that I'm gay cuz I thought that was the
most important part of the speech yeah
man that's what I'm talking about good
for you okay so uh he was going to come
out in front of the whole school right
so so what happened how did Evan end up
telling his parents that he was gay it
was Mr Bachman who called Evan's dad to
tell him he wasn't going to allow his
son's speech and it was also Mr Bachman
who told Evan's parents their son is
gay what Mr Bachman the principal he
outed Evan to his parents how' that call
go uh hey Mr Young just wanted to let
you know the PTA meeting got pushed back
to a oh and your son's gay got to run
a principal's job is to open up Life's
opportunities not to take away one of
life's biggest moments well you know
it's a shame that this kid couldn't make
his speech a speech about tolerance and
acceptance it'd be really great to hear
it which is why I flew him out here
please welcome reading his b the Curr
spee Evan Young
everybody very
good all
right this
one very
good we are responsive Evan uh welcome
to the show and congratulations on being
so brave and taking a stand we're all so
proud of you here's what we're gonna do
great we're gonna have you give kind of
in a bridge version of your speech
because I mean we're on television we
can't do the whole speech okay but it's
the speech you're going to give it your
graduation and uh and we're going to
throw the whole speech on the web so if
any of you want to see the whole speech
you can see it there okay now Evan this
is this is the speech that you wrote
These are your exact words right that's
right okay great Okay evan young ladies
and
gentlemen in the words of one of my
heroes Steven coar
[Applause]
drinks
um did you just say stepen Co bear um
you wrote that come on man well yeah
that's what's in the text of my speech I
don't care you can't say that crap on
this show man seriously who bought you a
roundtrip ticket with just one
layover you did I guess exactly I did
continue okay in the words of one of my
heroes Larry
Wilmore that's a valedictorian y' that's
a valedictorian okay now let's hear the
part you refuse to change go ahead I
won't all
right so since we're never going to see
each other again I thought I should
share several of my deepest and darkest
Secrets first I dislike doing homework
now not all homework is bad sometimes
it's helpful but like the heck maneuver
you're only supposed to do it when it's
absolutely
necessary otherwise you're just going to
make children throw up for no
reason Miss Gilmore I only read about
halfway through crime and punishment
before switching to spark notes for the
remainder of the
book and my biggest secret of all I'm
gay I understand this might be offensive
to some people but it's who I am when I
was writing
this when I was writing this speech I
was endlessly debating with myself
whether I should reveal this on account
of how divisive an issue this is and how
gay people tend to be stereotyped and I
thought that if I did I should
repeatedly apologize and beg you guys
not to think any different of me but
then I realized I don't have to I
shouldn't have to if there's one thing I
learned at this school it's that we can
still be friends even if we profoundly
disagree with each other so I have one
final request for you hug someone that's
right hug someone students hug a teacher
Democrats hug a
republican people who own a gun hug one
of those darn liberals who wants to
snatch out of your cold dead
fingers trekkies hug someone who like
Star Wars more no get Gibson hug a
Jewish
person conservative Christians hug an
agnostic hug a gay personally you're at
it too actually please don't cuz I don't
want to have to hug everyone here but
you get the
point and finally we're at the part
you've all been waiting for the end of
the speech goodbye everyone I'll miss
you and whatever happens to us and
wherever we go my only hope is that
we'll meet again don't know where don't
know when Evan Young
everybody good job
man